# Soma Ikeda - Frontend Developer

Vancouver, BC

□ 604 417 2682 | **Soma.gear@gmail.com** 

 $\fbox{ https://github.com/Soma-dev0808 } \rule{0mm}{2mm} https://www.linkedin.com/in/soma-ikeda-99b9741b6$ 

# Summary-

Highly resourceful Frontend developer with 4+ years' of experience bringing in-depth knowledge of latest technology trends to develop web applications. Experience integrating complex frontend system with React.js, Next.js and extensions to develop a company's product or customer's product. Experience developing APIs to support backend teams as a fullstack developer. Collaborated with with UI teams and Backend teams to integrate frontend features.

## Work Experience

#### Miidas Inc.

Tokyo, Japan May. 2021-August. 2022

Freelance Web Developer

- · Developed job agency service which has more than 500k users with 10+ developers using React.js, Next.js, Sass, and Docker.
- Developed and improved user search system by optimizing frontend side methods.
- · Created multiple react custom hooks which observe user status and search conditions.
- Converted react's class components to functional components of the legacy application in order to release a new version of application with Next.js.
- · Worked with UI/UX team to build and style new mobile-friendly websites and tested on both web and mobile applicaions.

### **IQVIA Solutions Japan Inc.**

Osaka, Japan Jan. 2021-April. 2022

Web Developer

- · Developed CRM application with more than 50 team memberrs using React.js, JavaScript and ASP.NET #C.
- · Implemented UI of time schedule page and task management page with React.js and Redux.
- Integrated some APIs with ASP.NET #C which provides data for task management system.
- Worked with tech lead closely to keep on track with project plan and timeline .
- · Worked in big project with more than 100 developers to develop company product.
- · Conducted maintenance and operation for both frontend and backend of deployed application.

#### Sprobe Inc.

Cebu, Philippines Oct. 2018-Dec. 2020

Web Developer

- Led and supported UI team of 3~5 to develop Image editing service and Accounting notice system.
- Developed and designed UI of some applications such as Image editing service and Accounting notice system.
- · Built Attendance management mobile application alone from scratch using Native script.
- Developed UI of more than 7 applications from scratch using React.js, Javascript, and Native script.
- · Integrated and hosted notification function along with Node.js and 3rd-party API.

## **Technical Skills**

Strongest Areas Web Development
Programming Languages Javascript, PHP, C#

**Libraries/Frameworks** React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, GraphQL, Vite, Webpack, Git

**Database** Postgres DB, MySQL, Firebase

Platforms Vercel, Heroku, AWS

## Education

Web and mobile app development - CICCC Bachelor of arts - Tenri University

Vancouver ,Canada Aug. 2022- now Nara, Japan Apr. 2014- Mar. 2018

## **Proiects**

React chat app

Portfolio URL: https://portfolio-lp-soma-dev0808.vercel.app/

r ditiono dic. https://portiono.ip/soma devodo.vercei.app/

React.js, Redux, Firebase

- Real time chat app allows user to communicate with other users and check realtime status of other users in the same chat room.
- Repository(https://github.com/Soma-dev0808/react-typescript-chat)

## Concentration(Card game)

Next.js, React.js, Redux, Firebase

- · A card game concentration. Within the limit time, you find all matches of 2 cards to win the game.
- Repository(https://github.com/Soma-dev0808/concentration)

#### **Spotify Clone**

Next.js, React.js, Recoil

- Spotify clone application which you can actually play a song.
- Repository(https://github.com/Soma-dev0808/spotify-clone)